[ar: Hans Wilhelm]
[00:04.55]Hi I am Hans Wilhelm.

[00:06.10]In this video in the LIFEEXPLAINED series
[00:08.10]I would like to explore with you the Luciferian Doctrine.
[00:12.11]Now you may know about Lucifer, but have you heard
[00:13.98]about the Luciferian Doctrine and how it influences
[00:17.41]our world today?

[00:19.98]To understand where it came from, we have to go back 
[00:21.73]to 11th century. All of Europe was in the firm grip
[00:25.35]of the Catholic Church. At that time the Church was
[00:28.29]sending thousands of men as crusaders to recapture
[00:31.48]the Holy Land and in particular Jerusalem which had
[00:35.17]fallen into Moslem hands.

[00:36.46]Now who were these men - these Crusaders? They came
[00:39.22]from all walks of life. The one thing they had in common
[00:42.02]was their belief in the Catholic teachings. However,
[00:44.46]when these men travelled to the Middle East they were
[00:46.96]suddenly exposed to many different beliefs and
[00:51.14]spiritual teachings that they had never heard before.
[00:52.96]These teachings came from Judaic and Islamic mystism. They 
[00:55.89]came from Egypt, from Greece and even from far way places 
[01:00.58]like India. 

[01:01.33]For some of these men they were a truly mind-blowing 
[01:04.71]experience. They also began to hear different 
[01:07.20]interpretations of familiar biblical texts - things they 
[01:10.96]had never heard in their church.  One particular passage 
[01:14.64]stood out: It was the story of the snake tempting Eve with 
[01:18.83]the apple. The Catholic Church had taught them that the 
[01:22.46]snake was Lucifer, or Satan, who deceived Eve by promising 
[01:26.14]that if she would eat from the forbidden tree she would 
[01:29.52]become like God. 

[01:32.16]Suddenly these men were introduced to a very different 
[01:35.02]interpretation. They heard that Lucifer was not evil, or 
[01:38.15]Satan, but the God who wanted to save and educate mankind. 
[01:42.83]In truth they called him "the Light Bringer" the real God 
[01:46.77]and that Yahweh or Adonai in the Bible was in actuality 
[01:50.43]the devil, the suppressor of mankind because he didn't 
[01:53.12]want Eve and Adam to know their true identity. This 
[01:56.81]teaching became the famous 'Luciferian Doctrine'.
[02:01.50]Now when these men returned home from the Holy Land they 
[02:04.18]continued talking about these new ideas and 
[02:06.68]interpretations. But they knew they could only do so under 
[02:08.81]strictest secrecy as the Church would torture and kill 
[02:11.56]anybody who would question or challenge their teachings 
[02:16.13]and authority. This eventually led to the birth of many 
[02:19.56]secret societies - most famously the Templars, the 
[02:24.74]Rosicrucian and the various Masonic orders. These very 
[02:27.31]mixed teachings, from many different occult traditions 
[02:31.77]were secretly studied, eventually enwrapped in rituals and 
[02:35.08]protected by gruesome and bloodcurdling oaths that the 
[02:38.08]members had to swear to ensure secrecy.
[02:42.50]But everything changed in the year 1888 when the founder 
[02:45.97]of the "Theosophical Society" - Madame Blavatsky - made 
[02:47.63]most of these teachings public in her famous book "The 
[02:52.89]Secret Doctrine"  which she spiced up with some of her own 
[02:55.20]fanciful imaginations. Central to Madam Blavatsky's 
[02:58.58]teachings was the Luciferian Doctrine. The first editions 
[03:03.27]of her book stated, that "Lucifer is the only God for our 
[03:06.14]planet". 
[03:07.39]No surprise that her magazine was also called "Lucifer"
[03:11.51]It was the beginning of what we now would call the New 
[03:14.45]Age. Originally it was promoted as the time when the 
[03:17.89]Lightbringer, Lucifer, would lead mankind to a new era of 
[03:22.58]tolerance and peace.

[03:23.83]Rudolf Steiner started off as the secretary of the German 
[03:29.83]Theosophical Society. He later founded the Anthroposophy 
[03:32.26]movement. Another famous person was Alice Bailey who 
[03:34.39]founded the "Lucifer Publication Company" in 1922.  Then 
[03:38.20]there was the well-known science-fiction writer H.G. Wells 
[03:41.64]who also published a book called "The New World Order" in 
[03:44.83]l940. With this book he promoted a world government and a 
[03:49.52]secular world-religion.

[03:52.39]Other important figures were Annie Besant and Charles 
[03:54.70]Leadbeater who thought they had found the future world 
[03:58.45]teacher in a 14 year old Hindu boy called Krishnamurti. 
[04:02.20]However, this did not work out as planned. Krishnamurti 
[04:05.21]eventually dissolved the entire organization.
[04:08.08]So the Luciferian doctrine is not only central to members 
[04:12.01]of highest degrees in some elite Masonic circles but also 
[04:15.39]expressed in several New Age teachings of today. 
[04:19.08]Lets look how doctrine influences our life.
[04:22.70]Here we have planet Earth where according to the 
[04:26.58]Luciferian doctrine the worldly affairs are ruled by the 
[04:32.14]God Lucifer. 

[04:36.08]Now as spiritual beings we come from the spiritual worlds 
[04:40.27]to incarnate for a very short life span here on Earth. 
[04:46.02]Most of us do it to clear up past karma or eventually 
[04:52.14]return to a higher spiritual sphere or return even to our 
[04:56.77]spiritual home - from where we all came.
[04:59.52]But if we forget who we are or don't believe in life 
[05:02.58]before or after death, we can easily be tempted to 
[05:05.02]dedicate our life to accumulation of riches, power, fame 
[05:10.95]and other stuff that makes us important and special. We 
[05:15.20]might even fall for some New Age guru teachings promising 
[05:18.70]unbridled riches and abundance.

[05:22.08]Our purpose here is to develop the kingdom within and not 
[05:27.02]the kingdom without. But if we want worldly riches our God 
[05:32.33]and orientation would naturally be this guy: Lucifer. The 
[05:37.58]"Only God for our planet" - as Madam Blavatsky put it. He 
[05:40.64]rules the worldly affairs and with that many heads of 
[05:44.76]Politics, Military, Finance, and Industry. But it does 
[05:50.45]come with a hefty price: Anybody who aligns himself with 
[05:52.76]this God of the World to obtain riches, power and fame and 
[06:00.70]so on enters a "Faustian Bargain". Chances are they will 
[06:03.70]become his servant after their physical death. Such 
[06:07.95]energies are never given for free.

[06:10.71]Now in addition, the Luciferian Doctrine also states that 
[06:13.58]we are God - which is also a very popular belief among 
[06:17.70]some New Age teachings. The danger is that when we think 
[06:21.01]we are God, we are convinced we can get away with 
[06:23.45]anything. We feel that we are only accountable for our 
[06:27.08]actions to ourselves. In other words, we could harm or 
[06:31.14]even kill somebody and justify it as something that 
[06:34.58]"simply had to be done" - without any guilt or remorse and 
[06:38.39]totally ignoring that such an action has created an 
[06:43.45]enormous karma for our soul. Somebody who thinks he is God 
[06:48.64]does not feel accountable to anybody except himself. 

[06:53.77]Finally, let's look around this world and see how powerful 
[06:59.45]the Luciferian influence already is. We see the evidence 
[07:03.33]everywhere in the wars, terrorism, exploitation, 
[07:06.08]suffering, greed and so on. It is based on the freemason 
[07:09.70]principle "ordo ab chao" "Order from Chaos" which 
[07:13.52]justifies any actions to bring the "New World Order" into 
[07:16.45]existence. Many see this as a totalitarian form of world 
[07:21.02]government.

[07:24.83]The goals of this New World order are not secret. They are 
[07:27.33]outlined in the "American Stonehenge" for anybody to see. 
[07:31.52]They are, "the Georgia Guidestones" - erected in 1980. It 
[07:35.95]is a huge granite monument in which 10 new guidelines are 
[07:40.39]engraved in 8 different languages. These guidelines are 
[07:46.20]supposed to replace the 10 commandments given to Moses.  
[07:48.39]Two of the most interesting guidelines say "that mankind 
[07:51.70]should be reduced to half a billion people only". That 
[07:55.70]means many must die for the benefit of a few. This will be 
[08:00.83]the result of the "order out of chaos". They also say that 
[08:04.39]family planning must be controlled by the authority to 
[08:08.26]keep the number down.

[08:11.26]It is not my goal to convince anybody about the existence 
[08:15.83]of the Luciferian doctrine. I merely offer and if it works 
[08:18.76]for you, fine and if it [does] not, thats okay too

[08:21.02]The material for this video I have taken from the books by 
[08:26.14]Armin Risi and Jan van Helsing but there are a lot of 
[08:30.20]books on this topic if you want to explore it further.

[08:34.39]Thank you for your company.